clickpoint.com 2018-05-17

# Privacy Policy | Clickpoint

We will collect, store, and use your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, the Law and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/79.

Personal data include all information that may refer to natural or legal persons, for example first and last names, postal address, e-mail address and telephone number. Simple navigation and consultation of the website do not generally involve the gathering of the User’s personal data and only relate to the processing in anonymous form of so-called navigation data. In compliance with the provisions of the Organic Law 15/1999 (Protection of Personal Information), we inform the User that the personal data communicated and gathered in the context of the registration process are held and processed by Clickpoint for the purposes listed below.

The User’s data are gathered and processed for the following:  
a) carrying out reporting activities with the client based on contractual agreements subscribed with Clickpoint  
b) administrative purposes and performing obligations under the law, for example, accounting, tax, or adhering to court orders;  
c) Having received specific consent, sending newsletters and marketing materials via email, periodically;  
d) Having received specific consent, receiving updates on our activities and new postings on our blog;  
e) Having received specific consent, receiving promotional notices on event invites, training, webinars, special promotions or participating in market research and analysis;  
f) In the case of curriculum vitae, exclusively for the selection process.

The legal ground for processing data is to render the site’s features functional following the user’s access or the execution of a contract to which the data subject is a party or the execution of precontractual measures adopted upon requests of the same. In the cases expressly stated, the legal ground for processing data is the consent freely given by the data subject.

Processing for the aforementioned purposes occurs manually or electronically, depending on the purposes for which the data are communicated. The User must provide personal data which are true and accurate and up-to-date for purposes of creating and managing the contractual relationship with Clickpoint and of utilising the Service.

The data shall be stored for a term that is strictly necessary for the management of the purposes for which the data was collected, in compliance with the law in force and the legal obligations. In any case, Clickpoint has enacted practices that prohibit the storage of data for an indeterminate term and therefore limits the storage term in compliance with the principle of minimising data processing.

The data-gathering will also be with a view to transferring the data in question to associated companies, subsidiaries, or companies carrying out functions closely connected with and instrumental to the Service.

The data collected, if necessary or fundamental to execute the indicated purposes, may be used by external third-party Processors, or depending on the case, disclosed to the same independent controllers and more specifically: The companies belonging to our corporate group, Individuals, companies, associations or groups of professionals that provide assistance and advice to our Company, entities or associations that provide services connected and instrumental to carrying out the above-mentioned purposes. 

The data collected may also be transferred abroad, to companies both belonging and not belonging to our corporate group, including countries outside the European Union, in the form and manner envisaged in the current law, guaranteeing, in any case, an adequate level of protection. 

In any case, personal data shall never be disseminated.

**Cookies**

Cookies are fragments of text sent by a server to a client (browser) and then sent back by the client to the server whenever the client accesses the same server. Cookies are used for purposes of authentication and tracking of sessions and for memorising specific information relating to Users who access the server. Clickpoint specifies that the data obtained from cookies are utilised by Clickpoint itself or by companies that collaborate with Clickpoint in order to ensure simpler and more immediate and rapid access to the Service, easier navigation on the site by the User and also for marketing purposes and for purposes instrumental to the Service. The data are not associated with the User receiving the cookie i.e. they are present in anonymous form. The user may always decide whether or not to accept the cookies of a particular website. These rules are defined autonomously by the User at browser level.

**Rights of the User**

It is possible to access, object to the processing or request the erasure, the modification or the updating of all the personal data collected by the Company, at any time, by exercising the right to limit the data processing and the movement of data, by sending an email to: privacypolicy@clickpoint.com

**Security**

Clickpoint undertakes to maintain the security of all data gathered using the relevant technical and organisational tools. In compliance with the provisions of the Organic Law 15/1999 (Protection of Personal Information) and the RD 1720/2007, the safety measures are aimed at reducing to the minimum the risk of destruction or loss of data and the risk of unauthorised access, and they include the possibility of limiting access to the data to authorised Clickpoint personnel alone. Clickpoint employees acknowledge that they are bound by standards of data security and data confidentiality.

**Cancellation of data**

All data is held only for a period of time strictly necessary for the purposes for which the data was gathered. Without prejudice to the right to immediately block the use of data for commercial and marketing purposes, it may prove necessary to hold the data for a further period of time for purposes of satisfying legal provisions or for accounting and administrative purposes.

**Modifications**

In the future, modifications to this Privacy Policy may be introduced for purposes of ensuring ongoing compliance with applicable legal rules. We invite Users to carefully read the rules applied by ourselves for the gathering and processing of personal data.

**Interest Based Ads and Retargeting**

Interest Based Ads are based on the anonymous information stored in the User’s cookie. Clickpoint will provide more relevant advertising. For example a User that visits Finance sites often will be categorized in the “Finance” segment, and will be served advertisements that are relevant to the interests.  
You may easily block Interest Based Advertising and Retargeting activities from Clickpoint by opting-out. To do so please visit [this page](http://site.clickpoint.com/privacy-opt-out/ "Privacy Opt-out").  
Note that you are always able to prevent cookies from any website from being installed on your computer by adjusting your browser settings. Also, if the cookie is deleted by the User, all profile data is removed.

**Applicable law and court of exclusive jurisdiction**

The parties agree that, to the extent permitted by applicable legal rules and international agreements, any disputes that happen to arise shall be submitted to the exclusive jurisdiction of the court of the area in which the Clickpoint registered office is located.

**Contact details for inquiries and requests**

For any questions and/or inquiries please send an e-mail to:  
**privacypolicy@clickpoint.com**

CLICKPOINT MARKETING SLU  
Av. Diagonal 458 2b – 08006 Barcelona (Spain)  
CIF B65692543

**Data Processor**  
The controller didn’t appoint a Data Processor because the Company does not fall within the GDPR 2019/79 specified range
